<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeff Sessions on Factopolis</title>
    <link>https://www.factopolis.com/person/jeff-sessions/</link>
    <description>Factopolis : Statements</description>
    
      <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    
    
    
      <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:50:27 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>
        DACA Contributed to a Surge of Unaccompanied Minors Illegally Crossing US/Mexico Border
      </title>
      <link>https://www.factopolis.com/person/jeff-sessions/2017-09-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.factopolis.com/person/jeff-sessions/2017-09-05/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <blockquote>
          The effect of this unilateral executive amnesty, among other things, contributed to a surge of unaccompanied minors on the southern border that yielded terrible humanitarian consequences.
        </blockquote>
        <p>
          <cite>— Jeff Sessions, press briefing</cite>
        </p>
        <h4>Claims:</h4>
        <dl>
          
            
            <dt>
              <a href="https://www.factopolis.com/claims/daca-contributed-to-surge-in-minors-crossing-southern-border/">DACA Contributed to a Surge of Unaccompanied Minors Illegally Crossing US/Mexico Border</a>
            </dt>
            <dd>
              <h5>The Truth:</h5>

              Not supported by the data.
            </dd>
          
        </dl>
        
          <h4>Fact Checks:</h4>
          <dl>
            
              
              <dt><a href="http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/statements/2017/sep/05/jeff-sessions/jeff-sessions-questionable-claim-daca-helped-cause/">PolitiFact</a></dt>
              <dd>
                <blockquote>… the data shows that the upticks at the southern border were already under way by the time DACA was announced, and that the trend line didn’t change significantly after the announcement. So the effect, if there was any at all, would have been too small to measure.</blockquote>
              </dd>
            
              
              <dt><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fact-checker/wp/2017/09/06/the-trump-administrations-claim-that-daca-helped-spur-the-2014-surge-of-minors-crossing-the-border/">The Washington Post</a></dt>
              <dd>
                <blockquote>There was a surge in unaccompanied children in 2014, two years after DACA was announced. But that does not mean DACA led to that crisis or even contributed significantly to it. A bigger factor appears to be the 2008 law signed by Bush — as well as violence and economic conditions in the countries the children fled. DACA may have helped foster a perception that Obama was lenient on illegal immigrants, but it is hard to draw a direct line, as Sessions and Trump strive to do.</blockquote>
              </dd>
            
              
              <dt><a href="http://www.factcheck.org/2017/09/spinning-facts-daca/">FactCheck.org</a></dt>
              <dd>
                <blockquote>All the government reports on the subject that we could find said that misinformation about U.S. immigration policy <em>may</em> have driven some to cross the border illegally. But these reports cited multiple reasons for the surge, primarily violence in Guatemala, Honduras and El Salvador.</blockquote>
              </dd>
            
          </dl>
        
      ]]></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>
        Sactuary Cities Have an Official Policy of Protecting Criminal Aliens Who Prey on Their Own Residents
      </title>
      <link>https://www.factopolis.com/person/jeff-sessions/2017-08-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.factopolis.com/person/jeff-sessions/2017-08-07/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <blockquote>
          To a degree perhaps unsurpassed by any other jurisdiction, the political leadership of Chicago has chosen deliberately and intentionally to adopt a policy that obstructs this country’s lawful immigration system. They have demonstrated an open hostility to enforcing laws designed to protect law enforcement — Federal, state, and local — and reduce crime, and instead have adopted an official policy of protecting criminal aliens who prey on their own residents.
        </blockquote>
        <p>
          <cite>— Jeff Sessions, press release</cite>
        </p>
        <h4>Claims:</h4>
        <dl>
          
            
            <dt>
              <a href="https://www.factopolis.com/claims/sanctuary-cities-have-official-policy-of-protecting-criminal-aliens/">Sactuary Cities Have an Official Policy of Protecting Criminal Aliens Who Prey on Their Own Residents</a>
            </dt>
            <dd>
              <h5>The Truth:</h5>

              Sanctuary city laws don&rsquo;t protect illegal immigrants who commit crimes, but rather those who don&rsquo;t.
            </dd>
          
        </dl>
        
          <h4>Fact Checks:</h4>
          <dl>
            
              
              <dt><a href="http://www.Politifact.com/illinois/statements/2017/aug/16/jeff-sessions/jeff-sessions-stretches-link-criminal-aliens-and-c/">PolitiFact</a></dt>
              <dd>
                <blockquote>Chicago’s sanctuary city policy does not protect undocumented people who commit crimes, despite what Sessions claims. Only the  microscopic sliver of ambiguity about conclusive data prevents us from labeling his statement &ldquo;Pants on Fire,&rdquo; our lowest possible credibility rating. Instead, we rate it False.</blockquote>
              </dd>
            
          </dl>
        
      ]]></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
